Welcome back to A push in under three
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So we already know from the
entirety of unit four that the north and
south at this time were essentially two
different countries with the north being
industry based and the south being
farming reliant. So now stuff is going
to happen in Europe. A series of
revolutions break out in Europe around
1848 and a potato famine breaks out in
Ireland which causes tons of immigrants
from Ireland and Germany to flood into
the US mostly all settling in northern
cities. They built ethnic communities to
preserve their language and culture but
not everybody welcomed them. But what
you should understand is truly how many
immigrants that came into the US. I mean
look at this graph and it's spike there.
Need I even say more? All right, enough
about migration, let's look at some
abolitionists. Even though abolitionists
were a minority in the north, they made
a lot of noise. As we've talked about
before, Frederick Douglass gave fiery
speeches including what to the slave is
the fourth of July exposing the
hypocrisy of American freedom. Harriet
Beecher Stowe wrote the book Uncle Tom's
Cabin exposing the horrors of slavery. A
book that was said to be so influential
that Lincoln supposedly said it started
the Civil War. Harriet Tubman in the
Underground Railroad helped enslaved
people escape to the north. The north
and south weren't just disagreeing. They
were on completely different planets at
this point. Immigration, economic
divide, and the fight over slavery kept
deepening sectional conflict making war
almost inevitable. On the screen now are
some AP style questions for this topic.
Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.